Yustynn Panicker

HP: +65 9697 7804 | email: yustynn@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/yustynn/ | Singapore

PERSONAL PROFILE

Passionate and competent in numerous technological fields. Strong analytical skill and coding ability, particularly in fullstack web development. Keen on solving problems, has extensive leadership and training experience. Currently studying a variant of applied mathematics and data analytics.

EDUCATION

Singapore University of Technology & Design (SUTD), Engineering Systems & Design

May 2016 - Sept 2019

- SUTD: Established in 2009 in collaboration with Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT)
- ESD: Engineering Systems and Design bachelor's degree, with specializations geared to artificial intelligence
- University Undergraduate Merit Scholar, expected by school to graduate magna cum laude

Udacity, Machine Learning Nanodegree

Oct 2017 - Present

- Self-initiated course on predictive modelling through Machine Learning, co-created by Kaggle
- Fully sponsored by Singapore's Info-Communications Media Development Authority due to passion for technology

Fullstack Academy of Code (in New York, USA)

Nov 2015 - May 2016

- Immersive coding bootcamp for fullstack web development (with the MEAN stack), 7% admission rate
- Elected Head of Hackathons: organized and led cohort's attendance of hackathons across several US states
- Stayed on as a Teaching Fellow after the course ended (less than 1 in 5 graduates offered the fellowship)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Xfers, Software Engineering Intern

May 2017 - Jul 2017

- Developed with Ruby on Rails and React.js, with bug fixes and features frequently integrated into production
- Played key role in determining overall frontend architecture, focused largely on the transition from Embedded Ruby to React.js

Singapore Armed Forces, Armoured Infantry Platoon Sergeant

Dec 2013 - Dec 2014

- Led platoon of 12 men in the support company of an armored infantry division
- Commanded armored vehicle (Bionix II) in numerous battle simulations
- Overall in-charge of administration of entire company (~120 men strong), liaising with HQ and other companies to coordinate supplies, training schedule and more.

RECENT LEADERSHIP APPOINTMENTS

Official University Degree Representative (Engineering Systems and Development)

Sept 2017 - Present

- Elected through popular vote by the ESD 2019 student body
- Representing 1 in 4 of the entire SUTD Class of 2019
- Liaison between faculty+staff and students, ensuring course quality and student welfare
- Organize events for the entire program, including staff, faculty and graduate students

Head of Workshops @ What The Hack

Sept 2016 - Oct 2017

- What The Hack: SUTD's inaugural nationwide hackathon, with 175 participants and >\$20k in cash funding
- Led subcommittee of 4, as well as shaped overall direction of hackathon in executive committee
- Sourced for and organized 6 workshops for participants on Open Data, Arduino, Computer Aided Design, Design Thinking, Entrepreneurship, and Hacking Hackathons

RECENT AWARDS

Singapore Airlines (SIA) App Challenge, Grand Prize Winner

Oct 2017

- Grand prize winner for Student Category, beating 150 other teams in a team of 4
- Created proof-of-concept solution to track emotion in interview videos & process speech, in order to automatically assess job applicants during preliminary interview rounds
- Won a trip to meet top technology companies in Silicon Valley, chaperoned and sponsored by SIA

Techfactor Challenge 2016/2017, Winner

Dec 2016 - Sept 2017

- TFC: Year-long entrepreneurship/technology competition by ST Electronics & Spring Singapore (government organizations) to develop products for improving the lifestyles of the elderly
- Developed modular wheel attachments to improve elderly walker mobility, while fitting into existing devices
- Champion team, won \$29,000 with 4 other teammates

Angelhack Singapore 2017, CityConnect Challenge Winner

June 2017

- Solo effort, designed and developed a cross-platform mobile app with Sketch, InVision and React Native
- Application for developing countries with limited ATMs. Uses others' wallets as distributed cash-storage facilities

Won \$1,000 + entry into Australia's largest Startup Accelerator

SELECT PROJECTS

Augmentation of SUTD's Learning Management System (Blackboard)

Aug 2016 - Present

- Self-initiated, designed and developed single-handedly as an unofficial extension for SUTD students
- Currently used by 25% of the SUTD's entire undergraduate population
- Packaged in one-click install chrome extension
- Adds batch download functionality to download all course/folder materials & aesthetic improvements

User Demographic Insights from Web Traffic Data

Sept 2017 - Present

- Working with Teralytics, a Swiss company focused on data-driven human mobility insights
- Developed multithreaded web scraper and parser to scrape 280,000 wesites
- Used web scraping, clustering and visualization to tie users to age and gender demographics
- Technology Used: Python (Pandas, Matplotlib, Requests, threading, etc), SQL

Holographic 3D Graph Visualizer, Controlled Through Hand Movements

Oct 2016 - Dec 2016

- Single-handedly designed and developed software for visually rendering any 3D function as a graph, as well as for rotating and translating the view of the graph using hand movements
- Technology Used: Unity3D, C#, Leap Motion

Girder Gus Online Platformer Game (www.girderg.us)

Jan 2016

- Built from scratch on the MEAN Stack + PhaserJS with 3 others from Fullstack Academy
- Developed much of the game, level editor and server
- Implemented 'ghost' feature in all levels, allowing players to race against their older playthroughs

SELECT SKILLS

Fullstack Web Development + Mobile App Development

Node & Express, MongoDB, SQL, React & Redux, React Native, Sass, JavaScript (ES6), HTML5+CSS3

Data Processing + Web Scraping

Python (NumPy, Pandas, Requests, BeautifulSoup, Matplotlib)

Miscellaneous

Bash, Vim (my primary text editor), Ubuntu (my secondary OS), Sketch (I use Mac for design), InVision